Tongchee Y. Yang

8638 Fawn Way

McCordsville, Indiana 46055

(317)523-5142

tcknyaj@gmail.com

Mechanical engineer with 12 years of experience in quality, management, heat treat, grinding and turning department. Experience with training operators and technicians, writing standard operating procedures, installing new machines, maintaining a budget and supporting production in a precision manufacturing facility.

### **Experience:**

### NTN Corp 2018~present

Anderson, Indiana

Process/Heat-Treat Engineer

- -Worked with outside contractor (machine riggers, electricians and pipefitters) to install 2 induction hardening machines, 2 tempering ovens and 4 transferring system
- -Developed new parts through induction hardening process

# **NSK Corp** 2017~2018

Liberty, Indiana

Process/Heat Treat Engineer A

- -Managed 3 Heat Treat Technicians
- -Controlled daily operations of 17 heat treat machines
- -Performed daily, monthly and annual maintenance on heat treat machines
- -Wrote Standard Operating Procedure on heat treat production procedures

- -Controlled induction hardening and tempering coils
- -Troubleshoot heat treat lines (total of 16 heat treat machines and 7 furnaces) through pneumatics, PLC, hydraulics and electrical.
- -Controlled heat treat quality by working with metallurgist
- -Worked with vendor to improve heat treat machines with latest technologies (ex: better prox sensors, color detecting sensors, digital data logger and etc)
- -Implemented Eddy Current NDT to check for surface flaw using FANUC robots
- -Prepared PPAP for new part numbers

## **Davis Manufacturing** 2016~2017

Denver, Colorado

Manufacturing/Project Engineer

- -Perform initial assessment of new parts to established procedures and processes within customer's specifications
- -Generate travelers and work orders with technical procedures, plans and engineering documentation in JobBOSS as required for manufacturing
- -Organized and purchased materials from component, raw material, machining, assembly and testing for projects based on BOMs
- -Participate in improvement activities such as 5S, Kaizen events and Value Stream Mapping
- -Excellent organization, decision making and problem solving skills within a team environment
- -Work directly and virtually with other engineers, project managers, management and production planners to meet daily production delivery schedules

**Chrysler** 2013~2015

Kokomo, Indiana

Skilled Trades Supervisor

- -Managed 10 skilled trades (Electrician, Mill-wright, Pipefitter, Machine Repairman and Toolmaker)
- -Wrote detail breakdown reports on multiple failure items and large investment items
- -Established preventative maintenance on machines
- -Updated key performance indicators on bottle neck process (efficiency of machine, machine downtime, machine mean time for repair and scrap ratio)
- -Implemented changes and improvements on bottle neck process to help improve safety, reduce cycle time by eliminating the deburr process (Improving the process by 15%) and prevent future breakdowns by implementing preventative maintenances.
- -Used PentaSAP to purchase machine components, material and tools.

#### **NSK Precision America** 2008~2013

Franklin, Indiana

Process/Heat Treat Engineer A

- -Updated and maintain macro programs for hard turning ball groove and shaft end work
- -Wrote CNC programs for journal work on CNC lathe
- -Budget and schedule CNC machine upgrades and new purchases
- -Worked with machine vendor on specking and installing new CNC lathe
- -Ensured shaft turning processes is capable of producing quality parts
- -Programmed Mitutoyo CMM to check ball screw nuts
- -Used 5 M's and 5 Why's method to solve production issues
- -Controlled shaft turning tools/inventories
- -Identified and implemented cost reduction and quality improvement projects for heat treat and turning department (ex: wrote Microsoft Excel program to improve traceability, worked with vendor to install vending machines for shaft turning department, and etc)

# **NSK Corp** 2001~2008

Liberty, Indiana

Process/Heat Treat Engineer B

- -Controlled daily operations of 15 heat treat machines
- -Performed daily, monthly and annual maintenance on heat treat machines
- -Wrote Standard Operating Procedure on heat treat production procedures
- -Controlled heat treat and tempering coils
- -Troubleshoot all heat treat lines (total of 16 heat treat machines and 7 furnaces) through pneumatics, PLC, hydraulics and electrical.
- -Controlled heat treat quality by working with metallurgist -Worked with vendor to improve heat treat machines with latest technologies (ex: better prox sensors, color detecting sensors, digital data logger and etc)
- -Implemented Eddy Current NDT to check for surface flaw (cracks, dents and nicks) Prepared PPAP for new part numbers

#### **Education:**

1996~2001

Bachelor of Science Mechanical Engineering Indiana University and Purdue University at Indianapolis Indianapolis, Indiana

References available upon request